

□ (+82) 010-2796-5866 | **☑** daeun.choi@kaist.ac.kr | **回** cheddarChoi | **i** daeun-choi-1103

Summary_

I am an undergraduate student of School of Computing, KAIST, and studying Bio&Brain Engineering as a double major. I am working as a research intern in KIXLAB(KAIST Interaction Lab), and have worked as a developer and designer in several fields. I'm interested in HCI, especially AI-infused creativity supporting tools, digital well-being, and healthcare.

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea Mar 2017 - Feb 2022 (Expected)

B.S. IN SCHOOL OF COMPUTING (DOUBLE MAJOR IN BIO&BRAIN ENGINEERING)

GPA: 3.87/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude, Expected)

Publication

Reflect, not Regret: Understanding Regretful Smartphone Use with App Feature-Level Analysis

ACM CSCW 2021 / BEST PAPER AWARD & METHOD RECOGNITION

Hyunsung Cho, DaEun Choi, Donghwi Kim, Wan Ju Kang, Eun Kyoung Choe, and Sung-Ju Lee

Paper in Review (about web style customization using NLP)

ACM CHI 2022 IN REVIEW

Participated as second author

Experience _____

KIXLAB(KAIST Interaction Lab)

Daejeon, Korea

Undergraduate Research Intern

Jan 2021 - Current

Research on enhancing user-side customization on website using AI recommendation system, voice, and clicks.

Completed KAIST URP(Undergraduate Research Participation) Program with this project.

(Title: Enhancing the UI Design Iteration and Feedback Process with Voice and Clicks)

NMSL(Networking & Mobile Systems Lab)

Daejeon, Korea

Undergraduate Research Intern

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

Research on feature-level fine-grained smartphone usage tracking and intervention development for digital well-being. This project was published as a paper in CSCW 2021.

LG CNS Seoul, Korea

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT INTERN

Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

- Participated IT core talent Academy program of LG CNS
- 5 weeks individual project as a software architect
- Architecting and implementing architecture for large scale web services by building AWS development/operation servers, web service infrastructure, and CI/CD server load balancing

Honors & Awards

AWARDS

Dean's List College of Engineering, KAIST

2020 Fall

 $Awarded\ to\ the\ students\ within\ the\ top\ 3\%\ of\ GPA\ in\ school/department.\ (Granted\ with\ a\ GPA\ of\ 4.3/4.3\ in\ 2020\ Fall\ Semester)$

SCHOLARSHIPS

KAIST Exemplary Conduct Scholarship

2019

Annually awarded to 20 undergraduate students (in exemplary conduct/volunteering/contribution categories)

Misook Lim Scholarship

2021 Fall

Awarded to female students who major in computer science in KAIST in every semester.

Teaching

Teaching Assistant CS101 Introduction to Programming

2019 Spring - Current

Projects

Student-led KLMS Redesign Team

UX Researcher & Designer

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

KLMS is the LMS system used by KAIST. KLMS was reorganized in the spring of 2021, which raised various usability issues. To solve this problem, we collected and analyzed inconveniences, presented new UI/UX guidelines, and prototyped new designs. It was conducted with the support of KAIST Center for Excellence in Learning and Teaching.

SPARCS

UI/UX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER Mar 2019 - Current

I am working as a designer/developer of KAIST's Special Board of Computing, SPARCS (System Programmers' Association for Research Computer Systems). Currently I am working on improving UI/UX of NewAra service (KAIST official student online community) to be more user friendly.

Extracurricular Activity _____

KAIST Undergraduate Research Participation(URP) Program

2021 Winter/Spring

TITLE: ENHANCING THE UI DESIGN ITERATION AND FEEDBACK PROCESS WITH VOICE AND CLICKS

President of Undergraduates of School of Computing

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020

Planning Committee of KAIST 50th Anniversary Student Conference

Jan 2020 - Feb 2021

Leader of Design&Website Team

HEAD OF DESIGN&TECHNOLOGY TEAM

KAIST Undergraduate Association

Feb 2020 - Jan 2021